What was that just now?
Kawachi
Yeah, okay...
I was just getting up.
Oh, I see. Got it.
Don't worry about it.
We'll meet up to bargain with them early next week, all right?
Talk to you later.
My maternal grandfather died last night.
That dream I had...
Was that Grandpa
and Mom?
It seems like he lost touch with all of our relatives.
I come back after all this time, and it's for a funeral.
I'm here.
Oh, Daikichi, you got here fast.
Just put your bags in Grandpa's room.
Okay.
By the way, there was a girl in the yard.
I can't remember, but is Haruko's girl around that age?
That wasn't Reina-chan.
Whose kid is she then?
Darn it! This kitchen is so inconvenient!
I don't know what to do from here on out.
Well, he was 79 and died a peaceful death, didn't he?
Apparently, that girl is Grandpa's illegitimate child.
Grandpa's child?!
Grandpa didn't say a thing about it.
His lover left him also.
His lover? He was 79!
It's so embarrassing, not to mention shameful.
Then she's
your little sister
and my aunt.
How can you make light of this?!
You're 30 years old, don't make such thoughtless remarks!
You died at peace, huh, Grandpa?
How much should I give?
Note: It's traditional to give money as condolences.
It's just a sign to express your good will, so any amount is fine.
I know, but there's a certain standard amount, isn't there?
Honestly, any amount is fine.
Although these days, it's common for sutras to be recited
Note: For such services,the priest is to be paid.
and a posthumous Buddhist name to be given.
She said it's around 400,000 to 500,000 yen.
That's a big sum of money.
Hello. It's been a long time.
Oh, Daikichi. Long time no see.
Have you been busy?
Yes, busy enough.
He always say he's busy! Even though mother wants to meet him so much.
He didn't even come home for New Year's.
Wait! Reina!
Stop it! Reina!
Haruko!
Oh, Dai-chan! Long time no see!
Mama!
Reina!
Gotcha!
Now be a good girl, and don't run around!
No way! I don't wanna!
What?
Nothing...
You look a lot like your grandfather when he was younger.
Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, from my mom earlier.
I wonder if it's true.
I'm sure my older brother was lonely living alone, but...
Apparently, there's a maternity health record book.
It says her name is "Rin."
Nevertheless, we're talking about a 79-year-old man.
Well, setting aside the question
of what your father might've done,
I think you've gotta give him props.
Daikichi, can you bring the cushions out of the closet for me?
Sure.
What is it?
Hey, hey.
Let's swap!
No!
Leave it like it is!
I did it!
Hey, look, look!
Reina, don't run!
Oh, how clever!
Is it pretty?
It certainly is! You're very good at Cat's Cradle, Reina-chan!
Try to make a four-square ladder next!
Oh, my, Reina-chan. Here, let me show you.
Poop bomb!
Hey, Reina!
Oji-san. Oji-san!
Please, sleep ahead of me.
I'll take my turn watching the incense.
O-Okay then.
Hey, don't sleep there!
Let's get some rest over there.
What about the incense?
Daikichi says he'll watch over it.
Come on now.
Take care of my big brother.
You get some sleep over there too.
I'm fine.
Look at that mug.
Kaga Souichi
All right, everyone.
Please make your final farewells.
Rest in peace.
Nii-san...
Ojii-chan...
Farewell.
Come along, Reina.
Okay!
It's time to say goodbye to Grandpa.
Okay.
Field of flowers!
Stop it!
No! I'm making a field of flowers!
I wanna make it!
Come over here, and say goodbye too.
Place this on Grandpa.
Hey!
A bellflower.
Grandpa loved that flower.
That flower makes Grandpa the happiest.
He's not going to wake up again?
No. He's not going to wake up.
You... really are Grandpa's child, aren't you?
Heisei
Buddhist's Memorial Tablet
2nd
Sep
tem
ber
Maternity Record Book
Where did this "Yoshii Masako" go?
I don't think it would do any good
to find the person who abandoned her child and ran away.
How utterly irresponsible!
My big brother was also stubborn about it.
That's dangerous!
That girl can't talk!
It's a pain!
And she still has all her baby teeth!
She can talk!
And she's not a pain!
She can't talk!
That's why it's so boring being with her!
Here! You can have all these if you go away.
You're like a candy shop owner!
Sorry, Dai-chan.
Setting aside the future,
who's going to take care of that child right now?
Well, I can't.
Not when running the store.
If only she were a little more proper...
She seems to be suffering from delayed speech, too.
Mom....
You're at home a lot. Why don't you take her in for a while?
Y-You know that'd be impossible!
I don't have that much free time on my hands!
Besides, do you even know how hard it is to raise a child?
Haven't I made enough sacrifices over the years?
I'd feel sorry for her if she came over,
and no one had time for her.
Wasn't this meeting supposed to be about who would take in Rin?
It's not like you have any intention of doing anything, do you, Onii-chan?
Think about the situation more realistically.
Even so, I'm not even certain that she is Grandpa's child.
See? You haven't thought it through, so you can't even give me a comeback.
For now, I say we try placing her in a facility as quickly as possible.
What?
Rin!
Want to come home with me?
Hey! Daikichi!
Onii-chan?!
Old man, I'm hungry.
O-Old man?!
Don't call me "old man"!
You're my aunt, after all!
Is it good?
Uh-huh.
More?
All we have left is rice.
I'll make a rice ball.
I don't have anything you can put in a rice ball.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey! That's still hot!
Look!
But it'll taste nice this way.
Here, Ojii-chan.
I mean, Daikichi!
"Daikichi" is strange too, you know.
It's good.